Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions and Organizations WEB.ARC.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Organization United for Respect at Walmart (OUR Walmart) Archived Website, Nov 25, 2012 - ongoing; Organization United for Respect at Walmart (OUR Walmart)
  Organization United for Respect at Walmart (OUR Walmart), is an organization which works to make change in labor practices for Walmart associates, established in 2011. The organization works to change policy at Walmart, including the following changes: paying a minimum of $13/hour and make full-time jobs available for Associates who want them; creating dependable, predictable work schedules; providing affordable healthcare; providing every Associate with a policy manual; ensuring equal enforcement of policy and no discrimination; and giving every Associate equal opportunity to succeed and advance in his or her career. The group's website publishes associate stories and provides action alerts.
  Service industries workers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Professional Aviation Safety Specialists (PASS) Archived Website, Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing; Professional Aviation Safety Specialists (PASS)
  The Professional Aviation Safety Specialists, AFL-CIO (PASS) represents approximately 11,000 Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) and Department of Defense (DoD) employees throughout the United States and in several foreign countries. PASS members include Technical Operations and DoD employees (systems specialists, electronics technicians and computer specialists), Flight Standards and manufacturing aviation safety inspectors, flight inspection pilots, missions specialists and procedures development specialists in Aviation System Standards, and administrative employees in the FAA’s Aviation Registry. In 1977, PASS was formed to provide representation for the FAA’s technician bargaining unit. PASS has grown over the decades and now represents five bargaining units within the FAA and DoD. PASS is dedicated to supporting and sustaining the safety and efficiency of the National Airspace System (NAS) for the flying public.
- Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York. Archived Website, Sep 24, 2007 - ongoing; Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York.
  The Professional Staff Congress is the union that represents more than 20,000 faculty and staff at the City University of New York (CUNY). The union negotiates, administers and enforces collective bargaining agreements; protects the rights of staff through the grievance and arbitration process; engages in political activity on behalf of CUNY and its staff and students; and advocates for the interests of the instructional staff in various forums. It is affiliated with the American Federation of Teachers (AFT), the American Association of University Professors (AAUP), the New York State United Teachers (NYSUT), and the NYC Central Labor Council (CLC).
  College teachers' unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Universities and colleges |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Progressive Librarians Guild Archived Website, Nov 24, 2008 - ongoing; Progressive Librarians Guild
  The Progressive Librarians Guild, founded in 1990, is a forum for open exchange of radical views on library issues. The Guild conducts campaigns to support progressive and democratic library activities; supports activist librarians as they work to effect changes in their own libraries and communities; bridges the gaps between school, public, academic and special libraries, and between public and technical services; encourages debate about prevailing management strategies adopted directly from the business world and to propose democratic forms of library administration; considers the impact of technological change in the library workplace; monitors the professional ethics of librarianship from a perspective of social responsibility; and facilitates contacts between progressive librarians and other professional and scholarly groups in the record keeping field. The Guild publishes a journal, the Progressive Librarian.
  Librarians--Political activity--United States.; Libraries and society.
- Radicals at Work Archived Website, Apr 1, 2011 - Sep 30, 2014; Radicals at Work
  Radicals at Work is a network of young activists and radicals involved in workers’ movements. The network works to build a stronger movement from the bottom-up. The website informs and educates on issues in the workers’ movement. The website has not been updated since mid-2010.
  Labor movement |x Political activity |z United States.
- Remember the Triangle Fire Coalition Archived Website, Sep 8, 2012 - ongoing; Remember the Triangle Fire Coalition, Inc.
  Remember the Triangle Fire Coalition, established for the centennial of the Triangle Shirtwaist factory fire, works to build of a public art memorial to honor the legacy of the Triangle factory workers and spread awareness of the fire through education and activism. The website contains information on the memorial design competition, an open archive of digitized material on the fire, labor activism in the early twentieth century, and the victims. The website also contains a names map, resources, and information about their centennial commemoration.
  Triangle Shirtwaist Company--Fire, 1911.
- Restaurant Opportunities Centers United Archived Website, Jul 4, 2011 - ongoing; Restaurant Opportunities Centers United
  Restaurant Opportunities Centers United (ROC-United), founded in 2001, is a national coalition of restaurant workers' organizations. It works to is to improve wages and working conditions for the nation’s low-wage restaurant workforce. ROC-United does extensive statistical research to understand the labor market in ROC-United regions.
  Restaurants |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.; Restaurants--Employees--United States
- Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union, Local 1-S, Department Store Workers Union Archived Website, Mar 17, 2009 - ongoing; Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union. Local 1-S Department Store Workers Union (New York, N.Y.).
  Local 1-S is a local branch of the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union/UFCW (RWDSU), which represents Macy’s workers in the United States and 3,500 employees at the Macy’s department store in Herald Square, Manhattan. The union works to protect Macy's employees' right to the fair wages and benefits that allow them to support themselves and their families. The website contains news, benefits information, contracts, and images.
  Department stores |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Service industries |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU) Local 3, United Store Workers Archived Website, Nov 6, 2013-ongoing; Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union. Local 3 (New York, N.Y.).
  Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union (RWDSU/UFCW), Local 3, founded in 1937, represents more than 2,000 sales clerks, shelf stockers and clerical workers at Bloomingdale’s flagship 59th Street store in New York City, with extended protection to workers at the Bloomingdale’s SoHo store. The website contains news and event listings, meeting minutes, contract information, and newsletters.
- SAG-AFTRA Archived Website, Feb 25, 2012 - ongoing; SAG-AFTRA
  The website contains information on the merger in 2012 of the Screen Actors Guild (SAG) and American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (AFTRA). It contains news related to the merger, events, frequently asked questions, and a page on merger materials.
  Actors |x Labor unions |z United States.; Motion picture industry |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.; Radio broadcasting |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.; Television broadcasting |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Screen Actors Guild (SAG) Archived Website, Dec 5, 2009 - Sep 20, 2012; Screen Actors Guild.
  Screen Actors Guild (SAG), established in 1993, is an American labor union representing over 200,000 film and television performers worldwide. According to SAG's Mission Statement, the Guild seeks to: negotiate and enforce collective bargaining agreements that establish equitable levels of compensation, benefits, and working conditions for its performers; collect compensation for exploitation of recorded performances by its members, and provide protection against unauthorized use of those performances; and preserve and expand work opportunities for its members. SAG merged with AFTRA in March 2012.
  Motion picture actors and actresses--Labor unions--United States.
- Screen Actors Guild, New York Branch Archived Website, Mar 10, 2009 - ongoing; Screen Actors Guild. New York Branch..
  The New York Branch of the Screen Actors Guild is one of twenty branches nationwide representing actors working in motion pictures, television, commercials, industrials, video games, Internet and all new media formats. The Guild exists to enhance actors working conditions, compensation and benefits and to be a powerful, unified voice on behalf of artists rights.
  Actors |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Motion picture industry |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Television broadcasting |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Service Employees International Union (SEIU) Archived Website, Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing; Service Employees International Union.
  Service Employees International Union (SEIU), founded in 1921, is a labor union representing about 1.8 million workers in over 100 occupations in the United States (including Puerto Rico), and Canada. SEIU is focused on organizing workers in three sectors: health care (over half of members work in the health care field), including hospital, home care and nursing home workers; public services (local and state government employees); and, property services (including janitors, security officers and food service workers). It is affiliated with the Change to Win Federation and the Canadian Labour Congress.
- Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents Archived Website, Apr 1, 2014-ongoing; Committee of Interns and Residents/SEIU Healthcare..
  The Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents is the largest housestaff union in the United States. It represents residents, interns and fellows in California, Florida, Massachusetts, New Jersey, New Mexico, New York, and Washington, D.C. It was founded in 1957 as the Committee of Interns and Residents to represent interns and residents in New York City hospitals. In May 1997, the Committee of Interns and Residents affiliated with the Service Employees International Union, and as of this writing [2014] represents over one million health care workers across the United States. The website contains information on benefits, alumni services, news, their magazine, "Vitals," and conference details.
  Hospitals |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.; Residents (Medicine) |z United States.
- Sheet Metal Workers International Association (SMWIA) Archived Website, Dec 8, 2009 -Jun 1, 2014; Sheet Metal Workers' International Association.
  The Sheet Metal Workers International Association, founded in 1888, is a trade union of skilled metal workers who perform architectural sheet metal work, fabricate and install heating and air conditioning work, shipbuilding, appliance construction, heater and boiler construction, precision and specialty parts manufacture, and a variety of other jobs involving sheet metal. The Sheet Metal Workers International Association represents about 150,000 members in 185 local unions in the United States and Canada.
  Metal workers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Sheet Metal Workers International Association. Local 137 Archived Website, Mar 11, 2009 - ongoing; Sheet Metal Workers' International Association. Local 137.
  The mission of the Sheet Metal Workers International Association, Local Union No. 137 is to organize, educate, and represent all workers in associated crafts in the New York region. The purpose of the Union is to represent all members in their fight to improve benefits, wages, and safe working conditions. The website contains event listings, a blog, images from events, and information on their apprenticeship program. In 2014, the Sheet Metal Workers International Association officially merged with United Transportation Union, and the website ceased to exist. To see current crawls of the local union please see http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1xp6x576.
- SMART Transportation Division General Committee of Adjustment GO 505 Archived Website, Jul 1, 2014-ongoing; International Association of Sheet Metal, Air, Rail and Transportation Workers.
  SMART Transportation Division General Committee of Adjustment GO 505 represents Long Island Rail Road workers in the greater New York Metropolitan area. The division oversees the administration of Local 29, track and bridge and building workers, Local 645, conductors, assistant conductors and special services workers, Local 722, car inspectors, car repairman & car appearance maintainers, and Local 1831, yard conductors. The website contains information on benefits, local meetings, event listings, letters from the general chairman, and news postings related to contract negotiations.
  Long Island Rail Road.; Transport workers |x Labor unions |z New York (State)
- SMART Union Archived Website, Mar 12, 2014-ongoing; International Association of Sheet Metal, Air, Rail and Transportation Workers.
  SMART Union is the website for the International Association of Sheet Metal, Air, Rail and Transportation Workers, the result of the 2008 merger of the Sheet Metal Workers’ International Association and the United Transportation Union. The union represents, over 216,000 members, including sheet metal workers, service technicians, bus operators, engineers, conductors, sign workers, welders, production employees, transport workers, and others. The website contains information on the sheet metal and transportation arms of the union, news postings, and action alerts.
  Sheet Metal Workers' International Association.; United Transportation Union; Metal workers |x Labor unions |z United States.; Transport workers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Social Service Employees Union Local 371 Archived Website, Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing; Social Service Employees Union. Local 371.
  Founded in 1965, Social Service Employees Union Local 371 is part of District Council 37 of the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees AFL-CIO (AFSCME), which represents workers employed by New York City in social service professions. The website contains information on benefits and grievance filing, and their current and past contracts.
  Social workers |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Social workers |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Southwest Workers Union Archived Website, Jul 3, 2012 - ongoing; Southwest Workers Union
  Southwest Workers Union, launched in May of 1988 in Hondo, Texas, is an organization of low-income workers and families, community residents, and youth, united in the struggle for worker rights, environmental justice and community empowerment. The union organizes 2500 members. The website contains resources and news.
- Starbucks Union (IWW) Archived Website, Jul 30, 2009 - ongoing; Starbucks Workers Union.
  The Starbucks Workers Union is an organization of employees at Starbucks (a coffee chain) united for a living wage, secure work hours, and respect on the job. They are affiliated with the Industrial Workers of the World.
  Food service employees |x Labor unions |z United States.; Syndicalism.
- Stella Doro Strike 2008 Archived Website, Aug 16, 2009 - May 5, 2011; Bakery, Confectionery, Tobacco Workers and Grain Millers International Union. Local 50.
  On August 13, 2008, over 135 members of Bakery, Confectionery, Tobacco Workers and Grain Millers International Union Local 50, employed at the Stella D'Oro plant in the Bronx, went on strike citing proposed pay and benefit cuts, and later picketed the company's attempt to bring in replacement workers.In early September 2010, a 2 to 1 ruling by the National Labor Relations Board affirmed the June 2009 decision of an administrative law judge that Stella D'oro violated federal labor law by refusing to furnish detailed financial statements to the workers' union to support claims of needing contract concessions to survive. The factory closed in October 2009. This website was a support page for the strike which posted news and other information.
  Kingsbridge (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions.; Strikes and lockouts |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Street Vendors Mobilizing and Organizing in Solidarity Archived Website, May 6, 2012 - ongoing; Street Vendors Mobilizing and Organizing in Solidarity
  Vendedoras Ambulantes Movilizando y Organizando en Solidaridad (VAMOS Unidos or Street Vendors Mobilizing and Organizing in Solidarity) is a Bronx based social justice organization, founded in 2007 by low income Latino/Latina street vendors. The organization works to organize Latino immigrants, for economic and racial justice, immigrant rights, and police accountability. The website contains information on provided services, news, photos, and videos.
  Street vendors
- #StrikeFastFood Archived Website, Sep 5, 2014-ongoing; Fast Food Forward; Low Pay is Not OK.
  In late 2014, Fast Food Forward merged with Low Pay is Not OK to form #StrikeFastFood. The organization is a movement of New York City fast food workers to raise wages and gain rights at work. They were formed after Thanksgiving 2012 from a small group of striking fast food workers. They goal is to raise the minimum wage to $15 an hour and the right to form a union without retaliation. The website contains information on past and future demonstrations and events, as well as news alerts related to the campaign.
- Teamsters for a Democratic Union Archived Website, Sep 27, 2007 - ongoing; Teamsters for a Democratic Union.
  Teamsters for a Democratic Union, founded in 1976, is a rank-and-file union democracy movement organizing to reform the International Brotherhood of Teamsters (IBT). TDU was created out of the merger of the Professional Drivers Council (PROD) and TDU in 1979. They represent truck drivers, dock workers, warehouse workers, and clericals.
  Labor union democracy |z United States.; Truck drivers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- The Seafarers International Union Archived Website, Apr 27, 2012 - ongoing; Seafarers International Union of North America.
  Founded in 1938, The Seafarers International Union, Atlantic, Gulf, Lakes and Inland Waters District/NMU, AFL-CIO, represents unlicensed United States merchant mariners sailing aboard U.S.-flag vessels in the deep sea, Great Lakes and inland trades. The union also represents licensed U.S. mariners in the Great Lakes and inland sectors. The website contains information on their training center, the Paul Hall Center for Maritime Training and Education, news, and stories.
- The Wage Project Archived Website, Nov 10, 2009 - ongoing; WAGE Project (Women Are Getting Even)
  The WAGE Project (Women Are Getting Even) is an organization that was established to end discrimination against women in the American workplace. The project offers resources and workshops to help close the wage gap. WAGE is led by Evelyn F. Murphy, author of Getting Even: Why Women Don't Get Paid Like Men and What To Do About It. Dr. Murphy is a Ph.D. economist, former Lt. Governor of Massachusetts; and by Annie Houle, National Director of Campus and Community Initiatives.
  Discrimination in employment |z United States.; Women |x Employment |z United States.
- Transport Workers Union of America Archived Website, Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing; Transport Workers Union of America.
  The Transport Workers Union of America (TWU) is a labor union that was founded in 1934 by subway workers in New York City. The TWU has four divisions: Railroad; Gaming; Airline; Transit; and Utility, University and Service. The Union has 114 autonomous locals representing over 200,000 members and retirees in 22 states around the country. The TWU is a member of the AFL-CIO and the International Transport Workers Federation (ITF). The website includes a blog, blogs related to different industries within the union, their political action committee, Committee On Political Education (COPE), their publications, TWU Express and ATD Insider, reports, conference materials, and images.
- Transport Workers Union of America Local 100 Archived Website, Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing; Transport Workers Union of America. Local 100.
  Local 100 is a local of the Transport Workers Union of America. The Local primarily represents workers in the New York City public transportation system and at some private bus lines serving the New York City metropolitan area.
  Subways--Employees--New York (State)--New York.; Transport workers |x Labor unions |z New York (State)
- UFT Alliance of Charter Teachers & Staff Archived Website, Nov 10, 2011 - ongoing; United Federation of Teachers.
  The United Federation of Teachers Alliance of Charter Teachers and Staff (UFT ACTS ) is a community of charter school employees organized by the UFT, which is a local union chapter of the American Federation of Teachers (AFT) and represents public school teachers, some private school teachers and other professionals in New York City. The UFT is affiliated with the statewide New York State United Teachers (NYSUT) and the national American Federation of Teachers (AFT). The UFT represents 13 charter schools in New York City.
  Charter schools |z New York (State) |z New York.; Teachers unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Union Communication Services Archived Website, Dec 8, 2012 - ongoing; Union Communication Services
  Union Communication Services, Inc. was founded in 1981 by David Prosten, a former publications and public relations director and staffer for several national unions. The website publishes and distributes steward advice, labor news, graphics and books that help progressive union leaders rally their members and build their unions. The organization is used by over 2000 unions in the United States and Canada. The website also contains a listing of every union website.
  Labor unions |v Directories.
- Union Jobs Clearinghouse Archived Website, Aug 7, 2009 - ongoing; Union Jobs Clearinghouse.
  Union Jobs Clearinghouse, is a site for posting the open staffing and trades positions in unions and allied organizations in the U.S. and throughout the world that are currently accepting applications.
  Employment agencies.; Labor unions |x Officials and employees.
- Union Label Archived Website, May 14, 2012 - ongoing; Union Label and Service Trades Department
  The Union Label and Service Trades Department, AFL-CIO, was founded in 1909 to promote the products and services produced in America by union members, specifically products and services identified by a union label, shop card, store card and service button. The website contains information on current boycotts, personal stories, news, a photo gallery, and their publication, the Label Letter.
  Union labels
- Union of Clerical, Administrative & Technical Staff, NYU Local 3882, NYSUT, AFT, AFL-CIO (UCATS) Archived Website, Sep 24, 2007 - ongoing; American Federation of Teachers. Local 3882 (Clerical Union).